Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty (VADP); Records apap304
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Legal, 1984-2022; 2; 3.2 cubic ft.; 2.31 GB
  - Nick Yarris, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Op-Ed About Senate Bill 1393 by Corinna Barrett Lain and Kevin C. Walsh "Against Lethal Injection Secrecy in Virginia", 2015 February 11
  - Op-Ed by Keith Harward, Draft, 2019 November 15
  - Op-Ed by Keith Harward, Second Draft, 2019 November 18
  - Op-Ed by Rachel Sutphin, Draft with MES Edits, 2019 October 30
  - Op-Ed by Rachel Sutphin, Draft with National Suggested Edits, 2019 November 4
  - Op-Ed by Rachel Sutphin, Final Draft, 2019 November 5
  - Op-Ed for Jim Reinhard, Draft with MES Suggested Edits, 2016 December 19
  - Op-Ed for Richmond Times by Keith Howard "Innocence enough reason to abolish the death penalty", 2019 December 22
  - Op-Ed for Richmond Times by Kristina Leslie "Death penalty repeal is essential to racial healing", 2020 July 2; 2020 July 13
  - Op-Ed for Roanoke Times by Bill Stanley "A conservative viewpoint on ending the death penalty", 2021 January 31
  - Op-Ed for Virginian Pilot "Virginia should seize this moment to abolish the death penalty", 2021 January 16; 2021 January 18
  - Op-Ed for Washington Post by Delegate Mike Mullin "Virginia must prevent wrongful executions", 2021 February 2
  - Op-Ed for Washington Post by Rachel Sutphin "End the death penalty in Virginia", 2019 November 24
  - Paul House, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Perry v. Texas, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Prosecutor Death Penalty Abolition Sign On Letter, 2020 January 6
  - Prosecutor Death Penalty Abolition Sign On Letter & Signatories, 2020 November 10
  - Prosecutor Death Penalty Abolition Sign On Letter & Signatories, Population, 2020 November 10
  - Prosecutor Death Penalty Abolition Sign On Letter, Endorsement Form, 2020 February 3
  - Prosecutor Death Penalty Abolition Sign On Letter, Final, 2020 February 3
  - Prosecutor Death Penalty Abolition Sign On Letter, Final, 2021 January 11
  - Prosecutor Death Penalty Abolition Sign On Letter, Press Release, 2020 February 3
  - Prosecutor Sign On Letter, Contact List, 2020 January 6
  - Quesinberry v. Taylor, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Racial Justice Act Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Review of Virginia's System of Capital Punishment, Undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Richmond Free Press Article "Virginia is poised to eliminate the death penalty", 2021 February 11
  - Richmond Times Dispatch Article "Appeals court upholds 'Norfolk Four' dismissal", 2011 April 21
  - Richmond Times Dispatch Article "Appeals court upholds 'Norfolk Four' dismissal", 2011 April 21
  - Richmond Times Dispatch Article "Convicting the Innocent" by Brandon Garrett, 2011 April 25
  - Richmond Times Dispatch Article "Convicting the Innocent" by Brandon Garrett, photograph, 2011 April 25
  - Roger Keith Coleman an Innocent Man on Death Row, Undated (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Satcher v. Commonwealth of Virginia, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - SB333 Fact Sheet, Undated (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Section 1912 Juvenile Death Penalty, Undated (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Senate and House Districts, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - Senate Bill 79 Mandatory Life Without Parole in Capital Cases, 2022 January 5; 2022 January 12
  - Senate Bill 79 Mandatory Life Without Parole in Capital Cases, Fiscal Impact Statement for Virginia Criminal Sentencing Commission, 2021 December 20
  - Senate Bill 116 Severe Mental Illness Exemption for Death Penalty, 2019 December 14; 2020 January 8
  - Senate Bill 116 Severe Mental Illness Exemption for Death Penalty, Fiscal Impact Statement for Proposed Legislation, 2019 December 10
  - Senate Bill 379 Death Penalty for Police Murder, 2022
  - Senate Bill 379 Death Penalty for Police Murder, Fiscal Impact Statement, 2022
  - Senate Bill 449, Death Penalty Abolition, Fiscal Impact Statement for Proposed Legislation, 2019 December 10
  - Senate Bill 449, Death Penalty Abolition, Senator Surovell, 2020 January 7; 2020 January 8
  - Senate Bill 790, Death Penalty for Killing Off Duty Police, 2016 August 25; 2017 January 11
  - Senate Bill 802 Serious Mental Illness Exemption from Death Penalty, 2018 January 10
  - Senate Bill 855 Determination of Mental Intellectual Disability in Capital Cases as Enacted, 2015 March 19
  - Senate Bill 1137 Serious Mental Illness Exemption from Death Penalty, 2018 December 30; 2019 January 9
  - Senate Bill 1137 Serious Mental Illness Exemption from Death Penalty, Fiscal Impact Statement for Proposed Legislation, 2018 December 19
  - Senate Bill 1137 Serious Mental Illness Exemption from Death Penalty, Substitute, 2019 January 14
  - Senate Bill 1137 Severe Mental Illness Exemption from Death Penalty, Rebuttal Arguments, 2016-2019
  - Senate Bill 1165 Death Penalty Abolition, Enrolled, 2021
  - Senate Bill 1165 Death Penalty Abolition, Senator Scott Surovell, 2021 January 8; 2021 January 13
  - Senate Bill 1231 Treatment of Incompetent Defendants in Capital Cases, 2019 January 4; 2019 January 9
  - Senate Bill 1393 Compounding Execution Drug Bill as Amendment, 2015 January 29
  - Senate Bill 1393 Compounding Execution Drug Bill as Amendment, Excerpt, 2015 February 5
  - Senate Bill 1393 Compounding Execution Drug Bill as Amendment, Excerpt, 2015 February 9
  - Senate Bill 1393 House Republicans Who Voted "No", 2015
  - Senate Bill 1393 House Republicans Who Voted "No" Meeting Summary, 2015 September 15
  - Senate Bill 1393 House Republicans Who Voted "No" Table, 2015
  - Senate Bill 1393 Urgent Action Alert, 2015 February 9
  - Senate Courts Communication Hearing, 2019 January 14
  - Senate Floor Debate on Severe Mental Illness Bill, Photograph 1, 2019 January 17; 2019 January 21
  - Senate Floor Debate on Severe Mental Illness Bill, Photograph 2, 2019 January 17; 2019 January 21
  - Senator Ben Chafin, Senate District 38, 2017 September 29
  - Senator David Sutterlin Biography, 2019 June
  - Severe Mental Illness American Bar Association National Op-Ed Timeline, 2016 June
  - Severe Mental Illness Bill, Draft, 2017 December 15
  - Severe Mental Illness Bill from Ohio, Article about Prosecutors Opposition, 2016
  - Severe Mental Illness Bill from Ohio, Responses to Opponent Arguments, 2016
  - Severe Mental Illness Exemption Film, 12 minute version, 2019 January 7
  - Severe Mental Illness Exemption Film, 21 minute version, 2019 January 9
  - Severe Mental Illness Exemption Initiative, Background Information, 2016
  - Severe Mental Illness Exemption Initiative Info Sheet from NAMI, 2016; 2015 December 9
  - Severe Mental Illness Op-Ed by Conservative Author, Draft, 2017 October 21
  - Severe Mental Illness Op-Ed by Conservative Author, Draft, 2017 November 7
  - Severe Mental Illness Op-Ed by Family Member, Draft, 2017 November 12
  - Severe Mental Illness Op-Ed by Family Member, Draft with MES Suggested Edits, 2017 November 21
  - Severe Mental Illness Op-Ed by Family Member, Draft with MES Suggested Edits, 2017 November 22
  - Severe Mental Illness Op-Ed by Family Member, Draft with MES Suggested Edits and Deletions, 2017 November 21
  - Severe Mental Illness Op-Ed by Murder Victim Family Members, Draft, 2017 November 3
  - Severe Mental Illness Op-Ed by Retired Judge, Draft, 2018 October 18
  - Severe Mental Illness Public Opinion Research Summary, 2015 November 30-2015 December 7; 2015 January 8
  - Severe Mental Illness Senate Action Alert Respondents, 2019 January 20
  - Sheppard v. Commonwealth of Virginia, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - Slezak v. Evatt, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Smith v. Angelone, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - Smith v. Murray, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - Social Justice University, Death Penalty Fact Sheet, Draft, 2020 September 27; 2020 September 21
  - Social Justice University, Death Penalty Fact Sheet, Final, 2020 September 27; 2020 October 7
  - Social Justice University, Death Penalty Fact Sheet, Revised Draft, 2020 September 27; 2020 September 22
  - Social Justice University, Death Penalty Fact Sheet, Updated Draft, 2020 October 30
  - Social Justice University, Death Penalty Fact Sheet, Updated Second Draft, 2020 November 11
  - Stanley "Tookie" Williams, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - State Capital Representation, Undated (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - State Senate District 1 Map with List of Localities, 2020 March 6
  - State Senate District 6 Map with List of Localities, 2020 March 30
  - Statement from NAMI Virginia on House Bill 794, 2016
  - Stickler v. Greene, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Stout v. Thompson, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Streamlined Procedures ACT, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Study of Virginia General Assembly Bills, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Summary of Virginia Legislative Battle on Execution Drug Secrecy Bill, Senate Bill 1393, 2015
  - Talking Points Against Senate Bill 1393 by Corinna Lain, 2015 February 9
  - Talking Points on Virginia Senate Bill 1393, Draft, 2015 January 27
  - Test of Death Penalty Exemption for Persons with Severe Mental Illness, Likely Voter Survey, Virginia, 2015 November; 2015 November 30-2015 December 7
  - Test of Death Penalty Exemption for Persons with Severe Mental Illness, Likely Voter Survey, Virginia Revised, 2015 November; 2015 November 30-2015 December 7
  - Testimony on House Bill 2263 Death Penalty Abolition, Rachel Sutphin, 2021 January 27
  - Testimony on Senate Bill 1165 Death Penalty Abolition, Kirk Bloodsworth, 2021 January 18
  - Testimony on Senate Bill 1165 Death Penalty Abolition, Rachel Sutphin, 2021 January 18
  - Testimony on Senate Bill 1165 Death Penalty Abolition, Richard Dieter, 2021 January 18
  - Texas Fair Defense Act, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Tidewater Legislative Table Proposed Issues & Death Penalty, 2021
  - VADP Allies List, 2011 April 8
  - VADP Amicus Brief, 2004; Undated (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - VADP Arguments in Support of Death Penalty Abolition, 2020 January 28
  - VADP Expansion Fact Sheet Senate Bill 1069 and Senate Bill 1409, 2009 January 16
  - VADP Flyer, Senate Bill 961 Triggerman Rule Expansion, 2009 January 16
  - VADP General Assembly Death Penalty Vote Tracker, 2009
  - VADP General Assembly Planning Documents, 2014-2022 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - VADP Members in Senator Chap Peterson District, 2018 December 14
  - VADP Meeting with Capital Defenders Agenda, 2017 May 10
  - VADP Support a Moratorium Flyer-Cost, 2009 January 16
  - VADP Support a Moratorium Flyer-General, 2009 February 25
  - Vernon Evans, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - VICPP Prayer Vigil Central Region, 2021 January 22
  - Virginia Catholic Conference, Senate Bill 1393 Talking Points, 2015 February
  - Virginia Catholic Conference, Senate Bill 1393 Ten Reasons to Slow Down, 2015 February
  - Virginia Code 21 Day Rule, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Virginia Criminal Code 18.2-31, Capital Murder Defined-Punishment, 2020 November 24
  - Virginia Department of Corrections Audit, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Virginia General Assembly, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Virginia General Assembly Death Penalty Bills, 1999; 2002 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Virginia General Assembly Materials, 1984; 1989-1991; Undated (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Virginia House Members, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Virginia House of Delegates- District Map, 2020 May 26
  - Virginia Mental Health Group, Contact List, 2015 November 19
  - Virginia State Senate Election, 2023 November
  - Virginia State Senate Members, 2015
  - Weeks v. Angelone, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - William Saunders for Execution Clemency, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Williams v. Pruett, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Williams v. Taylor, 1999; Undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Wright v. Angelone, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Wright v. Commonwealth of Virginia, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Publications, 1975-2008; 3; 2.6 cubic ft.
  Publications include newsletters, magazines, and studies that Virginians for Alternatives to the Death Penalty used to support ongoing efforts to abolish capital punishment. Flyers and pamphlets are also included in this series.
  This is the only series that does not contain any digital objects.
  - 100 Innocents Released from Death Row, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 1996 DPIC Report (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 1997 Death Penalty Year end Review (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 2000 Death Penalty Year End Report (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - ABA Journal The Death Penalty, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - A Call for Justice an Assessment of Access to Counsel and Quantity of Representation in Delinquency Proceedings, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Accountable to No one, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - A Christian Perspective, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ACLU 2003 Assembly at a Glance (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - ACLU 2004 Legislative Project (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - ACLU Bill Listings, 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - ACLU Fact Sheet, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - ACLU Legislative Alert, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - ACLU Legislative Alert, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - ACLU Legislative Project, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - ACLU Update, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - ACLU of Virginia, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - ACLU of Virginia Report, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Alaskans Against the Death Penalty, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "All but Death Can be Adjusted", Undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Arbitrary, Discriminatory, and Cruel", 2002 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - The Armband Protest Flyer, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Before the Virginia General Assembly, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Brochures, Undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - CACP Newsletter, 2002; 2004-2006 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - California Death Penalty, 2006; Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Campaign for Criminal Justice Reform Newsletter, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Capital Connections, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Capital Defense, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Capital Defense Handbook for Defendants and their Families, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Capital Losses: The Price of the Death Penalty in NY, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Capital Punishment, 1994; 1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Capital Punishment, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Capital Punishment 2000, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Capital Punishment 2001 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Capital Punishment, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Capital Punishment a Faith Based Study, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Capital Punishment for Female Offenders", 1991 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Capital Punishment Global Issues and Prospects, Undated (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Capital Punishment Study Resource, Undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Capital Punishment: What the Religious Community Says, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The Case Against Lethal Injections, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - The Case Against the Death Penalty, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "The Case Against the Death Penalty", 1992 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - The Catholic Opinion on The Death Penalty, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - The Catholic Radical, Undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - The Chair, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "Children and the Death Penalty", 2002 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - The Christian and Jury Duty, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Church of the Brethren, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - The Church Speaks: Capital Punishment, Undated (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Civil Liberties Review, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Common wealth of Virginia Citizen's Handbook, Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Commuted Prisoners, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Compassion, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Compassion Newsletter, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - "Constitutional Adjudication and the Death Penalty", 1906 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Corrections in America, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - "The Cost of the Death Penalty", 1983; 1987 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - The Crime Victims Report, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - The Criminal Justice Reformer, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Criminal Justice Research Built in, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Dead End, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Deadly Speculation, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Dead Wrong: an Examination of Prosecutions, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Death as a Penalty, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Death as a Penalty, Undated (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - The Death Penalty, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - "The Death Penalty", 1984 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - The Death Penalty, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Death Penalty Activism, Undated (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - "The Death Penalty and Restorative Justice", Undated (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Death Penalty Developments, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Death Penalty Essay, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Death Penalty Fact Sheets, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Death Penalty Fact Sheet, Undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Death Penalty Information Center, 1999 September 24 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Death Penalty in the USA, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Death is not Justice, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - The Death Penalty in 2003 Year end Report (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - "The Death Penalty in America", 1999 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - The Death Penalty in Black and White, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Death Penalty Information Packet, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - The Death Penalty: The Religious Community Calls for Abolition, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Death Qualifications as a Biasing Legal Process, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Death Penalty Reports, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Death Penalty Report, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Death Row- Conditions, Style Weekly Article, 1985 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Death Row USA, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Death Row USA, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Demand Justice, Undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - "The Deterrence Hypothesis", Undated (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Dignity Denied, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Disarming The State's Lethal Weapon, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Discipleship for Life, Undated (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - DNA Tests can Free the Innocent, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - "Does Capital Punishment Deter Crime", 2003 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - "Does the Government Waste You Tax Dollars", Undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - DPIC Fact Sheet, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - DPIC Update, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - "Drug Companies and Their Role in aiding Executions", 2002 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Equal Justice and Fair Play, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Equal Justice USA, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Failing the Future, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Fallibility vs. Penalty Study, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - The Forgotten Population, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - From FSO to Death Penalty Activist, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - "Foreclosed Impartially in Capital Sentencing Jurors and Predispositions to the Death Penalty", 1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Future of the Death Penalty in the U.S., 1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 2005-2006; Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "The Hourglass", 2003 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Human Rights Human Wrongs, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - I Don't Want Another Kid to Die, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - If You Cannot Afford a Lawyer A Report on Georgia's Failed Indigent Defense System, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Injustice, Guide to the 18th Annual Virgin Film Festival, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - The Innocence Alert, 2004; Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Innocence and The Death Penalty, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - "Innocence and the Death Penalty: Assessing the Danger of Mistaken Executions", 1993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - "Innocence and the Death Penalty: Assessing the Danger of Mistaken Executions", 1999 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - International Perspectives on the Death Penalty, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - International Standards on the Death Penalty, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Introduction to Criminology, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Israel Law Review, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Joe Giarratano, List of Supporters, 1990 October 3; 1991 February 9; 1994 April 14 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Judaism and the Death Penalty Handout, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Judaism and the Death Penalty, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - "Judges and the Politics of Death", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - "Jurors Views on Due Process and the Death Penalty", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Justice Quarterly, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Juvenile Death Penalty Brief, Undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - "The Juvenile Death Penalty in the US" Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - "The Juvenile Death Penalty Today", 2002 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "The Juvenile Death Penalty Today: Death Sentences and Executions for Juvenile Crimes", 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - "Kids Who Kill", 2000 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Killing Justice, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - League of Women Voters, 2004-2007 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Lethal Injection: Why Physicians Should Oppose It, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Life After Exoneration, Undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Lifelines, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Lifelines, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Lifetime Without Parole vs. The Death Penalty, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Mandatory Justice, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - "Mental Retardation and the Death Penalty", 1988 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - "Mental Retardation and the Death Penalty", 2004 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - "The Methods of Execution Prescribed by S.239 Are Unconstitutional", Undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Millions Misspent, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Ministering to Prisoners, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Moratorium News, 1999-2000; 2003-2004; Undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Moratorium Now, Undated (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Moratorium Now Packet, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Moratorium Packet, 2005; 2002; Undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Moratorium Resolution Draft, Undated (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - "Murder is Wrong", 2000 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - "Murder is Wrong No Matter Who Carries It Out", Undated (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Murder Victims Families Flyers, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - "The Mystery of Goodness", 1991 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - The National Prison Project Journal, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - National Weekend of Faith is Action Guidebook, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - The Next Step Pamphlet, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - National Weekend of Faith Pamphlets, 2004-2005; 2007 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - NCADP Conference Program, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Not in Our Name, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Not in Our Name, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - NYU Review of Lam and Social Change, 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - On The Front Line, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Open Letter to the President on the Death Penalty, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Organization of American States, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - The Other Side, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - "The Outrageous Lack of Fairness in Each Stage of Capital Proceedings", 1986 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - OUADT Update, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Position Paper, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Post Conviction Justice In Capital Cases, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Post Conviction Relief Mechanisms in Other States, Undated (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Prisoner Reentry What Works, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Program Report of the VA Coalition on Jails and Prisons, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Raise the Roof, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Reasonable Doubts, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - The Religious Community and the Death Penalty, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - "Responding to Murder", 1998 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - The Right to Counsel, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - "The Room With no Exit", 1984 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - The Snitch System, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Starving for Justice, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Statement of Ida Reid, Undated (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Stop it, 1992; Undated (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Sentencing for Life, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - So Long as They Die: Lethal Injections in the US, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Strategies for Abolishing the Death Penalty, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Stop Child Executions, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Stop Executions in Pennsylvania, Undated (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Stop Execution of Mentally Retarded, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Study Examines Race and Execution, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - TCASK Newsletter, 2005; Undated (Box 2, Folder 89)